Abdulraheem Quwam

Data Analyst

dev.abdulraheem@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdulraheem-quwam https://abdulraheemg.herokuapp.com/

Summary

Accomplished Data Analyst with extensive experience in predictive modeling and data processing algorithms, as well as scripting language including python. Capable of Providing actionable business intelligence to support strategic initiatives and implement the solutions derived to improve return on investment.

Experience

QueLib Python Package - Co. Founder

OCT 2022 - PRESENT

 Implementing the python programming language and several python packages to create the QueLib in other to make data cleaning and preprocessing much more easier.

Neo Docto Inc, Remote - Data Analyst Intern

JUL 2022 - OCT 2022

- Utilized analytical and technical expertise to provide insights and proposals to support business improvement.
- Conducted Business analysis to understand business needs and requirements to translate into conceptual designs.
- Analyzed and produced KPI reports allowing to monitor field service and customer care center closely.

The Sparks Foundation, Remote - Data Science Intern

MAY 2022 - JUN 2022

• Examined Informations using the data analysis tools provided by Python to make important decisions by identifying facts and trends in data.

- Submitting the reports to the managements to provide the insights about the new improvement.
- Build predictive models using various machine learning tools to predict the possibility of equipment failure.

EDUCATION

Talent Model College, Lagos - SSCE. Economics.

MAY 2013 - JULY 2019

Skills

- Python Programming Language
- Relational Database (SQL, Postgresql)
- Microsoft Power Bl, Microsoft Excel
- Machine Learning (Supervised, Unsupervised)
- Data Analysis, Effective Communication, Critical Thinking, Problem-Solving

Selected Projects

PepsiCo Data Science Challenge
FundRaising Prediction
Employee's Churn Prediction

Awards

Top performer, Data Science Nigeria Hackathon. Data Science Nigeria (DSN) is a frontline Artificial Intelligence (AI) non-profit committed to driving the solution-oriented application of Artificial Intelligence in Nigeria, with a focus on building world-class AI knowledge, research, and innovation ecosystem that delivers transformational research, business use applications, AI-first start-ups, employability, and good social use cases.